

Anton Forsman

in antonforsman () anforsm 🔶 anforsm

Summary

I am a Master's student in Machine Learning with industry and research experience in LLMs, multimodality and computer vision, mostly working with PyTorch. With data playing an important role in all areas of Machine Learning, I have much experience in building and designing data pipelines in Python and TypeScript, using model and data repositories such as HuggingFace, as well as setting up and querying SQL databases.

Experience

AI Sweden

NLU/NLP Intern

Stockholm, Sweden (now Remote)

June 2023 - Present

Worked full-time during summer and part-time since. I am working on their upcoming multimodal large language model. I created a data pipeline for processing 100,000+ hours of audio and related metadata. I am currently conducting experiments on model architectures, prompt- and data formats for embedding audio in LLMs. I have trained countless billion-parameter LLMs on a DGX server.

Working on manuscript

Harris' Lab at UT Austin

Master's Thesis Student

Austin. Texas

December 2023 - Present

Researching deep learning models for 3D image segmentation of electron microscopy images. Actively developing a training and post-processing pipeline for such models, currently in use by other researchers at the lab. Using SLURM to submit jobs on HPCs.

https://github.com/anforsm/autoseg

KTH Royal Institute of Technology

Teaching Assistant

Stockholm, Sweden

November 2021 - June 2023

Head Teaching Assistant in second cycle frontend development course with over 200 students. Notably, I developed real-time granular analytics tracking of students' progress on assignments. I also launched a unit- and integration-test suite for the course assignments.

Teaching Assistant in second cycle course in algorithms, data structures and complexity.

Auto-Maskin

C++ Developer

June 2021 - August 2021

Developed a plugin in C++ for importing circuit diagrams from TinyCAD to open-source software KiCad.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin

August 2023 - June 2024

Exchange Year during Master's Degree in ML (GPA: 4.0/4.0)

Won Ram's Horn Award for best class project in Digital Image Processing with Prof. Al Bovik. The project consisted of implementing a diffusion model from scratch.

https://github.com/anforsm/movie-diffusion

KTH Royal Institute of Technology

August 2019 - June 2024

Master's Degree in Machine Learning (GPA: 4.9/5.0)

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering (GPA: 4.6/5.0)

Ο.	 110

PyTorch	HuggingFace	Weights and Biases	Git	NumPy	
Pandas	Next.js / React	Linux	Docker		
Languages					
Python	SQL	TypeScript	C++	Bash	